Register of the Ralph E. Jennings Papers, 1918-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
Ralph E. Jennings Papers
1918-1966
71059
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes, 9 envelopes, 1 oversize box, 1 oversize folder (3.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, personnel records, memoranda, speeches, logbooks, clippings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to U.S. naval operations in World War II, the U.S.S. Yorktown, a historic telecast from the U.S.S. Leyte in August 1947, and the Military Assistance Group to Norway.
Jennings, Ralph E., 1897-1971
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biographical Note
1897, June 14 Born, New York City
1943 Rear Admiral
1943-44 Commander, U.S.S. Copahee
1944 Commander, U.S.S. Yorktown
1946-47, 1949-50 Commander, Fleet Aircraft, Alameda, Calif.
1947-49 Commander, Carrier Division, Atlantic Fleet
1950-52 Chief, Military Assistance Advisory Group to Norway
1952-53 Deputy Commander, Eastern Frontier and Atlantic Fleet
1953 Vice Admiral, U.S. Navy, Retired
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, personnel records, memoranda, speeches, logbooks, clippings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to American naval operations in World War II, the U.S.S. Yorktown, a telecast from the U.S.S. Leyte in August 1947, and the Military Assistance Group to Norway.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1971.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Copahee (Ship); Leyte (Ship); United States. Military Assistance Advisory Group to Norway.; United States. Navy--Officers.; Yorktown (Aircraft carrier, 2d of the name); Norway--Military relations--United States.; Norway.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Military relations--Norway.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.; World War, 1939-1945.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1918-1959 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Personal correspondence. Includes U.S. Navy personnel records, such as orders for duty, appointments and promotions, and pay and travel expense reports; memoranda and reports, including a memorandum on postwar organization of the military services, December 1944. Arranged chronologically
  - 1918-1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945-1948 (Box 2)
  - Includes undated correspondence, 1949-1959. (Box 3)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928-1966 (Boxes 4-5)
  Correspondence, reports, speeches, awards and citations, log books, ship's rosters, telegraphic communications, patent, newspaper clippings, and printed matter. Arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Aviators flight log books, July 1928 -August 1952 (Box 4)
  - Awards, citations, and letter of appreciation from the Secretary of the Navy
  - Battle of Philippine Sea. Includes a British Naval Air Observer's report, June 1944
  - Biographical sketches
  - "Functional Speaking for Naval Officers," a syllabus
  - Mementos
  - News clippings of foreign and domestic press about Admiral Jennings and his ships' visitations to foreign ports
  - Patent for skid indicator and related material
  - Printed matter, miscellaneous
  - Speeches by Ralph Jennings
  - Television broadcast of U.S.S. Leyte's maneuvers, August 1948
  - U.S. Military Commission to Norway, 1950-51
  - U.S.S. Leyte, pamphlets
  - U.S.S. Yorktown Association's 18th Reunion, August 27, 1966
  - U.S.S. Yorktown (Box 5)
    - Reports of strike attacks, March 1944
    - Roster of officers, 1944
    - Telegraphic communications to and from the U.S.S. Yorktown, February-July 1944
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1947 and undated
  - Photograph album of scenes of Turkey, 24 prints, undated (Box 6)
  - Photograph album concerning Jennings' mission to Turkey to reorganize the Turkish navy, 34 prints, undated (Box 6)
  - Photograph album entitled, "Souvenir of the Visit of the American Fleet to Tzinir, Sept 1947," 20 prints (Box 7)
  - Commemorative photo album of the USS Yorktown wartime activities, 120 prints, undated (Box 8)
  - 19 prints of Adm. Jennings and other important persons; 40 prints of crew members; 30 prints of USS Saratoga and USS Yorktown; 48 prints of ceremonies involving Adm. Jennings; 97 prints concerning visitations of Adm. Jennings' shops to foreign and domestic ports; 34 prints of World War II naval combat scenes; 70 aerial photos of bombing raids conducted by planes from the USS Yorktown; 12 prints of aircraft, undated (Envelope A-H)
  - 1 envelope of 40 prints of World War II combat scenes; 1 picture book, "U.S. Navy War photographs, Pearl Harbor to Tokyo Harbor.", undated (Envelope mI)
  - 5 prints (oversize and not in envelope) including a group photo of participants in the 1928 National Air Races, aerial photos of naval maneuvers, and 2 photos of maps, undated (Map case)